(比企谷)何の用ですか？
わざわざ呼び出して
What'd you call me out here for?
(陽乃)約束の答え合わせを
しようと思って➡
I thought we could check answers, like we promised.
雪乃ちゃんの進路は聞いた？
Did you find out what future course Yukino-chan picked?
一応 知ってますけど
I do know, yes...
But it wouldn't be fair for me to be the one to tell you.
それを俺が言うのは
フェアじゃないんで
Ah, how dutiful of you.
ありゃ 義理堅い
でもそっか
比企谷君にはちゃんと教えたんだ
Still though... she actually told you.
へえ～ 雪乃ちゃんに
ずいぶん信頼されているんだね
Yukino-chan really trusts you, huh?
信頼っていうか
そういうんじゃないでしょ 俺は
I wouldn't call it trust...
I don't think that's what it is, in my case.
何だ 自分で分かってるんだ➡
Oh, so you do realize it.
You're right. It's not trust.
そう あれは信頼とかじゃないの➡
もっと ひどい何か
It's something much more cruel...
≪(陽乃)何も変わってない➡
Nothing's changed.
それでいいと思ってるのよね
あの子は➡
And she thinks it's fine that way.
そこがまあ かわいいところでも
あるんだけど
That's part of what makes her so cute, but still...
そこが すごく気に入らない
It's what I can't stand about her.
信頼じゃないなら何なんですかね
If it's not trust, then what is it?
Who can say?
さあ ただ少なくとも
それを本物とは呼ばない➡
But at the very least, I wouldn't call it the real thing.
君の言葉だったね
Those were your words, right?
本物なんて…
Does that "real thing" even exist?
あるのかな
♬～
(戸部)べ～ッ
何か甘いもの食いたいわ～
Man...
I wanna eat something sweet!
あれじゃね？
チョコっとだけ食べたくね？
Know what I mean?
Don't you wanna eat a little chocolate?
(優美子)はッ？
(葉山)そういえば もうすぐか
Huh?
Get it? A little chocolate?
Yeah, it's almost that time, isn't it?
(大岡)隼人君はいいけどよー
俺らマジ ヤバイから
You'll be fine, Hayato-kun, but we're in big trouble.
Yeah, but you know,
やー でもほら 隼人君
バレンタインのチョコとか➡
Hayato-kun doesn't usually accept Valentine's chocolates.
基本 受け取らねえしさ
Seriously?
≪(大岡)マジで？ もったいねえ
What a waste!
(結衣)でも
よく知らない人からもらうのって
But it's kinda scary getting it from someone you don't know well, right?
何か怖いもんね うん
Well, yeah, giving handmade is kinda heavy...
まあ 手作りとか ちょっと重いし
受け取らないのも分かるかも
I can understand why he wouldn't accept those.
Heavy?
<重い… そう だよね>
That's true...
≪(戸部)チョコだけに やっぱさ
ワンチャンあるで➡
うん チョコっとだけ
Just a little chocolate?
<手作り… か>
Handmade, huh...
何で先行くし
いや 一緒に行くとか言ってないし
Why'd you leave first?
Wait, I never said I'd go with you.
待っててくれたのかと思ってた
I thought you were waiting for me.
ヒッキーしばらく教室にいたし
You stayed in the classroom for a while...
いや 葉山と三浦の様子を
ちょっとな
No, I was just checking out how
Hayama and Miura were doing...
ああ うん もう平気みたい
Oh... Yeah. I think they're okay now.
何かさ いいよね ああいうの
That kinda thing is nice, isn't it?
ちゃんと今を
大事にしてるっていうか
It's like they really treasure what they have right now.
今が一番いいっていうか
Like the present time is the best time...
Yeah.
そうだな 今が一番かもしれないな
Maybe the present time is the best time.
お～ ヒッキーにしては
珍しくポジティブ
Wow! That's unusually optimistic of you, Hikki!
Recalling the past dredges up regrets that make me want to die,
過去を思い出せば
後悔で死にたくなるし
and when I think of the future,
the anxiety just makes me depressed.
未来を考えれば
不安でウツになるから
By process of elimination, you could say right now is my happiest time.
消去法で今は幸福って言えるな
It was pessimistic after all!
やっぱりネガティブだった
You're so quick to say stuff like that...
すぐ そういうこと言う
お前 そのうち暇な日ってあるか？
Do you... have any free days coming up?
ええッ？
Y-Yeah... Um, probably...
うん ええと 多分
大体 暇は暇 というか…
I'm pretty much free... I guess...
L-Let me think about it.
ちょっと考える
あッ ああ
S-Sure.
Yahello!
やっはろー！
(いろは)先輩 遅い
Senpai, you're late!
だから 何でお前がいるんだよ
And again, why are you here?
ところで先輩
どうでもいいんですけど
By the way, Senpai,
not that it matters, but do you like sweets?
甘いものって好きですか？
I think Hayama would be glad to eat anything you give him.
葉山なら何でも喜んで
食べると思うぞ
でも 隼人君 チョコ
受け取らないって言ってたよ
But they were saying Hayato-kun doesn't accept chocolates.
ええッ 何でですか？
さあ…
What?! Why not?
I'm not sure...
(雪乃)もめるからに
決まっているでしょ
Because it would cause arguments, obviously.
In grade school, the mood in the
小学校の頃 大体翌日は
教室の雰囲気がｷﾞｽｷﾞｽしていたわ
classroom the following day was always strained.
(一同)ああ…
じゃあ この際 先輩でもいいです
甘いものって好きですか？
Okay, then I guess you'll do, Senpai.
Do you like sweets?
その質問おかしいだろ
That's not the right way to ask that.
Hikki...
ヒッキーは甘いもの好きだよ
does like sweets!
そうね
Yes, he does.
I'm not sure why you two answered that, but...
なぜ お二人が答えたのか
アレですけど…
That's perfect, then!
なら ちょうどいいですね
何が？
Uh, what is?
甘さをどれくらいにするか
悩んでたんですよね➡
I wasn't sure how sweet I should make them.
人によって
好き嫌いあるじゃないですか
Everyone has different tastes, right?
どれくらいって 一色さん
自分で作るつもりなの？
How sweet? Are you planning on making your own?
Surprising.
意外だな
何でですか
Why is it surprising?!
I'm really good at making sweets!
私は お菓子作り得意ですよ
Anyway, so I thought
まあ そんなわけで義理チョコの
参考にしようかと思いまして
I could use you as a reference to make obligatory chocolate.
義理チョコなあ
Obligatory, huh?
Oh, are you one of those guys who's never gotten chocolate before?
あ～ 先輩 チョコ
もらったことない系ですか？
Hikki...
ヒッキー ちゃんともらえるもん
will get chocolate.
ねッ？
Right?
うん？ それって…
Huh? Does that mean...
That's right.
フン そうだ
俺には小町がいるからな
I've got Komachi, you know.
Komachi? Who's that?
こまち？ 誰ですか？
The rice?
お米？
お米じゃねえよ
She's not rice.
Oh, Komachi-chan is Hikki's little sister.
ああ 小町ちゃんはね
ヒッキーの妹
シスコン？
バカ 違えよ
Sister complex?
Idiot! No!
それは 否定できないかも
I'm not sure I can deny that.
So you do like younger girls, Senpai.
≪(いろは)やっぱり先輩は
年下好きなんですね
そんなことないし
I do not.
大体 お前 ４月生まれで
実際の差は１年未満だから
Besides, since your birthday's in April, there's less than a year between us,
あんまり年下って印象ないし
so I don't really think of you as younger than me.
何だよ？
What?
Uh, nothing...
いえ ちょっと意外だったので
I was just a little surprised.
こわッ 何で誕生日知ってるの？
Whoa, scary! Why do you know her birthday?
That's creepy, Hikki! Seriously creepy!
ヒッキー キモい
いやマジ キモいから
You certainly know her well.
ずいぶん 詳しいのね
いや 一色が前に自分で言って
あざとく無駄アピールしてたし
No, Isshiki said it herself the other day,
when the little sneak was trying to look pointlessly appealing.
Pointlessly?! It wasn't pointless!
無駄ですと？ 無駄じゃないですよ
And I'm not a sneak!
ていうか あざとくないですし
むしろ先輩の方があざといですし
You're a bigger sneak than I am!
(ノック)
≪(優美子)何ていうの？
How do I put it?
手作りチョコとか
作ってみたいんだけど
I want to try making chocolate.
その… 来年 受験だし➡
We'll be studying for exams next year...
だからまあ １回くらいなら
試しにやってもいいかな～とか…
So I figured I could at least try it once.
Yumiko, didn't you say giving handmade is kinda heavy?
優美子
手作り重いっつってたじゃん
W-Well...
そッ それは…
Hey, I think handmade is a great idea.
(海老名)まあまあ
いいと思うんだよ 手作り
ヒキタニ君も隼人君と
友チョコすればいいじゃん
Hikitani-kun, why don't you make friendship chocolate for Hayato-kun, too?
いや しないから ていうか
あいつ受け取らねえんだろ？
Not happening.
He doesn't accept chocolate anyway, does he?
男子同士ならセーフだよ
前提がアウトじゃねえか
It's okay if it's between boys!
What you're assuming is not okay.
そうなんですよね
That's right...
受け取らないって言ってる以上
難しいんですよね
If he says he won't accept any, that makes it tough.
ホントそれ
That's for sure.
<ヤダな～ 怖いな～>
Yikes, they're scary.
それで 何か用かしら？
So, did you need something?
Er... Well...
(川崎)あッ ええと…
つーか あーしの話
まだ終わってないんですけど
You know, I wasn't done talking yet.
はッ？ あんた
お茶飲んでるだけじゃん
What? You're just drinking tea.
What?
まあまあ サキサキも
何か話あったんでしょ？
Now, now...
Sakisaki, you had something to say, too, right?
とりあえず 話してみそ
Just tell us about it.
その… チョコのことなんだけど
Well... It's about chocolate...
あんたも誰かにあげんの？
ウケる～
You want to give someone chocolate?
That's hilarious.
What?
ああ？
はッ？
What?
Look, could you stop assuming I'm like you?
あのさ あんたなんかと
一緒にすんのやめてくんない？
What?
はッ？
あッ？
What?
Stop! Please play nice!
<やめて！ 仲よくして！>
で チョコが何だって？
And?
What about chocolate?
妹が作ってみたいんだって
My sister said she wants to make some.
Is there a kind that even a little kid can make?
何か小さい子でも
できるやつってない？
小さい子でもね…
That even a little kid can make...
でも サキサキ
家事 得意じゃなかったっけ？
But, Sakisaki, aren't you good at housework?
私の作るの 何か地味だから
The stuff I make is sort of plain...
あんま 小さい子 喜ばなさそう
I'm not sure a little kid would like it.
What kinds of things can you make, anyway?
ちなみに どういうの作れるの？
(一同)うん？
さと… さッ
Sim—
S—
さといもの煮っころがし
Simmered taro balls.
<地味だ>
Yeah, that's plain.
いいんじゃない？ ほら私
全然料理できないから
I think that sounds nice!
I mean, I can't cook at all, so I think that's amazing!
そういうのすごいと思う
ねえ？ ゆきのん
Don't you, Yukinon?
Yes.
そうね 煮っころがしと
ねっころがしってちょっと似てて
"Nikkorogashi" sounds a bit like "nekkorogashi,"
何だか かわいい感じがするものね
so it sounds rather cute.
That was a weird comment to follow up with!
フォローの仕方がおかしい
猫 関係ねえからな
Cats have nothing to do with anything.
けれど困ったわね
This is quite a problem, though.
はい 三浦先輩がちょっと本気を
出しつつあるのは困りものです
Yeah. It's kind of a problem that Miura-senpai seems to be serious about this.
I was talking about the number of requests for help we've received.
私が言いたかったのは
依頼の数のことなのだけれど
でもさ 何か
隼人君の気持ちも分かるな
I kind of understand how Hayato-kun feels, though.
あッ ほら 何てーか
Well, I mean, you know...
It would probably give me all kinds of weird ideas about stuff...
やっぱり色んなことに
気を回したりするんじゃないかと
Oh... That sounds like you, Yui-senpai.
ああ 何か結衣先輩らしいですね
そう… かな？
You... think so?
私らしい… か
That sounds like me, huh?
まあ 言い訳があれば
いいんじゃねえの
Well, wouldn't you just need an excuse, then?
葉山が納得できる建前っつーか
Like, a front that's convincing to Hayama.
Huh?
はッ？
受け取らざるをえないというか
If he has no choice but to accept them...
Or if the situation makes it natural for him to accept them,
受け取るのが自然な状況なら
話は別だろ
it's a different story, right?
In other words,
つまり エクスキューズが
あればいいということね？
you mean she just needs to have an excuse?
(結衣･いろは)はあ？
For example, instead of saying it's for Valentine's,
例えば ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝつーんじゃなくて
if you just ask him to taste-test it, he'd probably eat it.
試食してくれってことなら
葉山も食うだろ
Probably. Not that I'd know.
多分 知らんけど
そっか
一緒に作っちゃえばいいのか
That's it! We should make some together!
いいじゃないですか それ
That's a great idea!
依頼に来た人まとめて
イベント的な
It'll be like an event for all of us who came with requests,
where Yukinoshita-senpai can teach all of us how to make it!
で 色んな人が雪ノ下先輩に
教えてもらう感じで
Y-Yes... That would be fine with me...
えッ ええ
それは構わないけれど
あッ 副会長？
企画書の提出を命じます
Hey, Vice President? I'm gonna need a project proposal!
私は？
由比ヶ浜さんは…
What about me?
Yuigahama-san...
私と一緒にやりましょう
You can make some with me.
信頼ゼロ！ うう～
You don't trust me at all!
じゃあ ヒッキーはどうする？
Uh, then what should Hikki do?
俺は料理とか作れねえぞ
構わないわ
I can't cook.
That doesn't matter.
味見して感想をくれればいいのよ
You can taste them and give your opinions.
それなら任せろ 得意分野だ
Now that I can do. It's my best subject.
≪(いろは)はーい じゃあ
よろしくです
Okay, thanks.
というわけで
細かいとこはやっとくので
So anyway, I'll handle the details.
お料理教室 よろしくです！
Let's have a cooking class!
Chiba Mihama Takasu Community Center
Takasu Community Festival
Pre-Valentine's Day
Cooking Class
(玉縄)前回のｲﾍﾞﾝﾄがﾘｱｸｼｮﾝよくて
Yeah, the reaction to our last event was great,
バズも かなり上がってさ
and it generated a lot of buzz.
今後もｱﾗｲｱﾝｽ活動を
継続していきたいね
I hope we can continue working in alliance from now on.
Me, too.
ですね～
君達もいたのか？
Y-You guys are here, too?
ああ 言ってませんでしたっけ？
Oh, didn't I tell you?
う～ん ﾒｰﾙﾍﾞｰｽのやりとりには
ﾛｸﾞがなかった気が…
Well, I don't think I have a log of it in our e-mails...
<何だそれ かわいいな お前>
What the hell? You look way too cute.
(折本)会長
そろそろ始めたいんだけど
Hey, Pres, we'd like to get started.
ああ それじゃあ➡
All right, then...
This is a business chance, as well.
これってﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽﾁｬﾝｽでもあるよね…
We can use crowd funding to raise funds...
どうしたんだ？ あいつら
What's with them?
合同にして向こうからも
予算を引っ張れるなら
It's best if we can make this a joint effort
and pull some of the budget from them, right?
ベストじゃないですか
And luckily for me, it saves me the cost of obligatory chocolate!
私も義理ﾁｮｺの代金が浮いて
ﾗｯｷｰみたいな
R-Right...
おッ おう…
その考えはともかくとして
Well, that idea aside...
思いのほか優秀なのよね 一色さん
You're more impressive than I thought, Isshiki-san.
ひゃっはろー
Yahello!
姉さん
ごめん 遅れちゃった
Nee-san...
Sorry I'm late.
Anyway, this is today's special instructor, Haru-san-senpai.
というわけで今日の特別講師の
はるさん先輩でーす
どうも～ はるさん先輩でーす
Hi! I'm Haru-san-senpai!
何で この人呼んじゃったの？
Why did you ask her to come?
Well, she seems like a total veteran at this stuff, right?
だって
超百戦錬磨っぽいじゃないですか
私だけで十分なのに
I would have been sufficient on my own...
チョコレートを刻んで湯せん
Cut up the chocolate and warm it with hot water.
粗熱を取って 型に流し込む
Then let it cool and pour it into molds.
That's it?
そんだけ？
まあ 基本はそうね
Well, basically, yes.
ふーん ちょろくない？
Huh... That seems kinda easy.
甘いよ 優美子！ 湯せんって
You're naïve, Yumiko!
Warming it with hot water doesn't mean you put it in hot water!
お湯の中に
入れるってことじゃないんだよ
You do it more like this! Like this!
何か ｸﾞﾜｰｯてやんの ｸﾞﾜｰｯて
本当に連れてきてよかったの？
You really don't mind me bringing her?
I don't see a problem with it.
まッ いいんじゃねえの
そっか 京ちゃん
どういうお菓子食べたい？
Yeah?
Kei-chan, what kind of candy would you like?
(京華)うなぎ！
Eel!
O-Oh, really?
おッ おう そうか
Sorry!
ごめん この間
家族でうなぎ食べて
O-Our family had eel the other day, and she really liked it...
それから
すごく気に入ったみたいで
海外では男性から
贈り物をする方が一般的で
In other countries, it's common for men to give the gifts.
今回は そういうｸﾞﾛｰﾊﾞﾘｾﾞｰｼｮﾝを
意識した方が…
I think we should focus on that sort of globalization.
You really thought this out.
よく考えたな
これなら みんな自然に振る舞える
This way,
they can all act natural.
おかげで戸部も喜んでるよ
It's even made Tobe happy.
チョコ！
チョコも戸部も どうでもいいけど
Chocolate!
I don't care about chocolate or Tobe.
特に戸部
ハハッ ひどいな
Especially Tobe.
That's harsh.
≪(優美子)隼人～
Hayato!
お前 マジで料理得意なんだな
You're really good at cooking.
何ですか 口説いてるんですか？
What is this? Are you hitting on me?
甘いものだけに甘い言葉を
ささやけば いけるとか
If you think whispering sweet nothings will work because I'm making sweets,
then you're being naïve. You're gonna have to try again.
考えが甘いので出直してください
ごめんなさい➡
I'm sorry.
えい！
Here!
先輩 こういう甘いのは
嫌いですか？
Senpai, do you dislike sweet things like this?
I guess you'd call it a difference in awareness between Japan and other countries.
日本と海外では
意識の差っていうのかな➡
カルチャーギャップがあるよね
比企谷 チョコの型 余ってない？
Hikigaya, got any extra chocolate molds?
Uh, sure.
あッ おう
ありがとう
Thanks!
そういえば 私 比企谷に
あげたことあったっけ？
Come to think of it, did I ever give you chocolate?
はッ？
いや ねえだろ
そっか アハハハ
No, you didn't.
Oh, okay!
じゃあ 今年あげるよ
I'll give you some this year, then.
いや あ そう？
Er... Uh, really?
そういえば 隼人は昔
雪乃ちゃんからもらったよね
Speaking of, Yukino-chan gave you chocolate once, didn't she?
≪(葉山)ああ あったね➡
Yeah, she did.
小学校上がる前くらいに
陽乃さんと一緒にもらったことが
Right before we started grade school,
she gave some to both you and me.
で 雪乃ちゃんは
誰にあげるつもりなの？
So, who are you giving yours to, Yukino-chan?
別に姉さんには関係ないわ
I don't see what that has to do with you.
You didn't say you're not giving it to anyone.
誰にもあげないとは言わないんだ
やっぱり誰かにあげるんだね
So you are giving it to someone.
Well, there are only so many people you could give it to...
≪(陽乃)まッ 雪乃ちゃんが
渡す相手なんて限られてるけど
バカバカしい 勝手に言ってなさい
This is nonsense. Say whatever you wan—
(ボウルが落ちる)
ごめんなさい
いや…
S-Sorry!
It's okay...
<何で動揺してんだよ>
Why is she all flustered?
<そんな姿見たら
こっちが動揺すんだろ>
Seeing her like that is gonna make me flustered, too...
(二人)あッ
Don't get flustered...
<動揺するなよ>
ふふん ゆきのんも まだまだだね
You've still got a way to go yourself, Yukinon.
私はボウルとか
調理器具の扱いは完璧だから
I'm a master at handling bowls and cooking utensils!
いや お前はそれ以外のところが
致命的だろ
Yeah, it's the rest of it that you're fatally flawed in.
(タイマー終了)
(平塚)いいイベントになったな
This turned out to be a great event.
はあ よく分からんｲﾍﾞﾝﾄですけど
Yeah. It's an event I don't really get, though.
それでいいのさ もともと君は
よく分からんやつだ➡
That's just fine.
You're a guy who doesn't really get much, anyway.
君が関わった人間も
よく分からんやつらだ➡
The people you're involved with with don't get much, either.
It's only natural it would turn out this way.
こうなるのは当然だろ
Saying I don't get much is kinda mean...
よく分からんって
ひどくないですか？
Well, I guess you understand a little more now than you used to.
まあ 昔よりは多少
分かるようにはなったか
人の印象は
日々更新され続けている➡
Your impressions of people are renewed every day.
一緒の時間を生きて 一緒に
成長し続けていれば分かっていく
As you spend time with them
and grow with them, you come to understand more.
I don't particularly feel like I've grown.
別に成長した気はしないですけど
いつも同じことやってますよ
I always keep doing the same things.
歩いている最中は進んだ距離を
振り返らないものさ
When you're walking, you don't look back at the distance you've covered.
もっとも 歩みを
止めてしまった者からすると➡
Of course, from the viewpoint of someone who stopped walking,
進んだ距離の分だけ➡
the more distance they've covered, the more betrayed they feel.
裏切られたようにも
感じるものだが
今 近い場所で
この光景を見られてよかったよ
I'm glad I got to see all of this up close now.
いつまでも
見ていてはやれないからな
Because I won't be able to watch you guys forever.
Hikki! Try these!
ヒッキー これ食べてみて
よし 食う
All right. I'll eat it.
You look like you're preparing for the worst, but don't worry.
悲壮な覚悟をしているようだけど
大丈夫よ
I made them with her.
一応 私も一緒に作ったから
Oh, that's a relief, then.
何だ なら安心だな
何か ひどいこと言われてる？
Did you just say something really mean?!
Well, so...
まあ あれだ
ありがとな
Thanks.
うん！
Sure!
ふーん
それが比企谷君の言う本物？
Is that the "real thing" you were talking about?
こういう時間が君の言う本物？
Are times like these your "real thing"?
どうでしょうね
I'm not sure...
これがそうなの？➡
Is this it?
君は そういう子じゃないと
思うけど
I don't think you're that kind of guy.
君は そんなつまらない子？
Are you that boring?
面白いやつだったら
クラスの人気者になってますよ
If I were interesting, I'd be the most loved guy in my class.
そういう部分は好きよ
I like that side of you.
でも 今の比企谷君達は➡
But the way you guys are being now...
なーんか つまんない
is kind of boring me.
私は 前の雪乃ちゃんの方が
好きだな
I liked you better before, Yukino-chan.
<ただ 慣れていないから>
I'm just not used to it.
<経験したことがないから>
I've never experienced it before.
<だから ただの違和感なのだと
思っていた>
I thought it just felt a little awkward because of that.
<次第に慣れて
受け入れるのだと思っていた>
I thought I'd get used to it, and eventually accept it.
<それでも その違和感を
見逃してはくれなかった>
But you just wouldn't overlook that awkwardness.
あとは生徒会でやりますから
大丈夫ですよ
The student council will handle the rest, so you don't have to worry.
でも最後まで手伝うよ
We'll still help out until it's over.
Yes. There's no need for any reservation.
ええ 変に遠慮する必要はないわ
Really?
そうですか？
じゃあ お言葉に甘えて
Okay, I'll take you up on that.
<今まで
考えないようにしていたことを>
Yukinoshita Haruno attacks me with the things
<雪ノ下陽乃は 突きつけるのだ>
that I've always tried not to think about.
<それは信頼などではない>
It's not trust.
<もっとひどい
おぞましい何かだと>
It's something more cruel...
Something repulsive.
母さん どうしてここに？
Mom? Why are you here?
(母)陽乃からあなたの進路の話を
聞いたからよ
Haruno told me about the future course you've chosen.
雪乃 あなた
こんな時間まで一体何を？
Yukino, what have you been doing until this late hour?
あなたは そういうことを
しない子だと思っていたのに➡
I thought you were a child who wouldn't do these sorts of things...
あなたを信じているから
自由にさせていたけれど
I let you live your own life because I trusted you...
いいえ 私の責任➡
No. This is my responsibility.
私の失敗ね
It was my mistake.
私が悪いのかしら
Was it my fault?
Um...
あの 今日は生徒会のイベントで
There was a student council event today, and... we were helping...
その… お手伝いを
I see. And you were walking her home?
そう 送ってくれたのね
ありがとう
Thank you.
でも あまり遅くなると
But if you're out too late, I'm sure your family will worry, as well.
あなたの おうちの方も
きっと心配するわ ねッ
Yes?
(母)あなたには自分らしく
自由に生きてほしい
I want you to live your own life, and be who you are.
でも 間違った道に
行ってしまうのは心配で
But I'm worried that you'll take the wrong path.
ちゃんと説明するわ
I'll explain everything.
だから今日は もう帰って
So please, go home for today.
<彼女らしさ 俺らしさ>
Who she is... Who I am...
<きっと誰かが規定した自分を
ずっと持っていて>
I think there's some part of us that's pre-determined by others,
<それは いつも ずれている>
and that part is always a bit off.
<自分達らしくありたい けれど>
We want to be who we are.
But who, exactly, decides "who" that is?
<その自分は
一体 誰が決めたのだろう>
じゃあ 私帰るね
W-Well, I'm gonna head home.
ああ 送る
いいの
Oh... I'll walk you...
It's okay.
何か ずるい気がするから
I feel like it wouldn't be fair.
そうか
Okay.
<俺達らしさは いつもどこかで
食い違っていて>
"Who we are" is always clashing with us somehow.
<なら 本物は>
So where is the real thing?
<本当の俺達は>
Where is
With the Answer He Seeks Still Out of Reach,
the Real Thing He Craves
Keeps Going Wrong.
<どこにいるのだろう>
the real "us"?
#13     Spring Always Comes to Life Buried Underneath a Pile of Snow.
♬～
There's something I want.
But I'm not smart or anything,
and it wouldn't be fair.
There's only one answer for me.
But I'm sure it's not the answer that everyone else wants.
What I desire and what's desired of me are so similar,
so why are they so different?
The truth is, I wouldn't care if it was a lie...
欲しいものがある でも頭が
いいわけでもないし ずるいから
自分の答えは一つだけ
だけど それはきっと
望まれている答えじゃないと思う
欲しいものと
望まれているものは
とっても よく似ているのに
何で こんなに違うんだろう
本当は 嘘でもいいのに